Guide to the Bureau of Applied Social Research records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Articles
  - Segal, David R. and Marshall W. Meyer "Levels of Political Integration:A Contribution to the Theories of Mass Society.", (1966?), (14 pages ) (Box 140, Folder A 452)
    [Unpublished paper]
  - Sieber, Sam. "The United States Experience." Proceedings of the Anniversary Invitational Conference. Emerging Strategies and Structures for Educational Change., Ontario Institute for Studies in Education, Toronto, Canada, June ,1966, (pp. 162-169. ) (Box 140, Folder A 473)
  - Weiss, Carol H. "Interviewing Low-Income Respondents: A Preliminary View." Welfare in Review, Washington, D. C.: U. S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Welfare Administration, October, 1966, (pp.1-9. ) (Box 140, Folder A 462)
  - ______ "Planning an Action Project Evaluation." Learning in Action: Selected Issues in Training and Demonstration Projects, June L. Smelzer, ed., Washington, D.C.: Office of Juvenile Delinquency and Youth Development, Welfare Administration, U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1966, (pp. 6-21. ) (Box 140, Folder A 476)
  - Bahr, Howard M. "Drinking, Interaction, and Identification: Notes on Socialization into Skid Row." Journal of Health and Social behavior, Vol. 8, no. 4, December, 1967, (pp. 272-285. ) (Box 140, Folder A 509)
  - ______ "The Gradual Disappearance of' Skid Row." Social Problems, vol. 15, no. 1, Summer, 1967, (pp. 41-45. ) (Box 140, Folder A 480)
  - ______, and Stephen J. Langfur. "Social Attachment and Drinking in Skid- Row Life Histories." Social Problems, Vol. 14, no. 4, Spring, 1967, (pp.464-472. ) (Box 140, Folder A 477)
  - Benedict, Barbara A., Paula Holzman Calder, Daniel M. Callahan, Harvey A. Hornstein, and Matthew B. Miles. "The Clinical-Experiment Approach to Assessing Organizational Change Efforts." Journal of Applied Behavioral Science, Vol. 3, no. 3, July-September, 1967, (pp.347-380. ) (Box 140, Folder A 504)
  - Bisco, Ralph L. "Social Science Data Archives: Progress and Prospects." Social Science Information, Vol. VI, no. 1, February, 1967, (pp. 39-74. ) (Box 140, Folder A 471)
  - Brunner, Edmund de S. "Evaluation Research in Adult Education." International Review of Community Development, no. 17-18, pp. 97-102., 1967 (Box 140, Folder A 526)
  - Clark, Terry N. "Discontinuities in Social Research: The Case of the Cours Elementaire de Statistique Administrative." Journal of the History of the Behavioral Sciences, vol. 3, no. 1, January, 1967, (pp. 3-16. ) (Box 140, Folder A 453)
  - ______ "Marginality, Eclecticism, and Innovation: Rene Worms and the Revue Internationale de Sociologie from 1893 to 1914." Revue Internationale de Sociologie, serie II, vol. 3, no. 1-3, 1967, (pp. 1-18. ) (Box 140, Folder A 545)
  - ______ "Social Research and Its Institutionalization in France: ACase Study." Indian Sociological Bulletin, vol. IV, no. 4, July, 1967, (pp. 235-254. ) (Box 140, Folder A 516)
  - Cole, Stephen, and Jonathan R. Cole. "Scientific Output and Recognition: A Study in the Operation of the Reward System in Science." American Sociological Review, vol. 32, no. 3, June, 1967, (pp. 378-390. ) (Box 140, Folder A 460)
  - Etzioni, Amitai. "Nonconventional Uses of Sociology as Illustrated by Peace Research." The Uses of Sociology, Paul F. Lazarsfeld, William H. Sewell, and Harold L. Wilensky, eds., New York: Basic Books, 1967, (pp. 806-838. ) (Box 140, Folder A 508)
  - ______ "Toward a Theory of Societal Guidance." The American Journal of Sociology, vol. 73, no. 2, September, 1967, (pp. 173-187. ) (Box 140, Folder A 500)
  - ______, and Edward W. Lehman. "Some Dangers in 'Valid' Social Measurement." Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, vol. 373, September, 1967, (pp. 1-15. ) (Box 140, Folder A 499)
  - Fischer, George. "Sociology." Science and Ideology in Soviet Society, George Fischer, ed., New York: Atherton Press, 1967, (pp. 1-46. ) (Box 140, Folder A 513)
  - Glaser, William A. "International Survey of Sheltered Employment: A Summary of the Findings." International Rehabilitation Review, Quarterly of the International Society for Rehabilitation of the Disabled, vol. XVIII, no. 3, July, 1967, (pp. 17-18 ) (Box 140, Folder A 490)
    [Also Phoenix News, vol. 7, no. 3, December 1967, pp. 7-8, 2 copies.]
  - Gordon, Jerome B. "Occupational Classification: Current Issues and an Interim Solution." Proceedings of the American Statistical Association, Social Statistics Section, 1967, (pp. 277-288. ) (Box 140, Folder A 524)
  - Hjelm, Howard F., and Sam D. Sieber. "Emerging Institutions Related to Research." Theory Into Practice (College of Education, The Ohio State University), vol. VI, no. 2, April, 1967, (pp. 89-94. ) (Box 140, Folder A 469)
  - Hopkins, Terence K., and Immanuel Wallerstein. "The Comparative Study of National Societies." Social Science Information, vol.Vl,no.5, October, 1967, (pp. 25-28. ) (Box 140, Folder A 486)
  - Jaffe,A. J. "From New Entries to Retirement: The Changing Age Composition of the U.S. Male Labor Force by Industry." Demography, vol. 4, no.1, 1967, (pp.273-282. ) (Box 140, Folder A 481)
  - _______ "Pensions, Labor Productivity, and Inflation." The New York Statistician, vol. 18, no. 8, April, 1967, (pp. 5-6. ) (Box 140, Folder A 479)
  - ______,Walter Adams, and Sandra G. Meyers. "The Sharply Stratified World of the Negro Colleges." College Board Review, no. 66, Winter, 1967-68, (pp.20-28. ) (Box 140, Folder A 482)
  - Kadushin, Charles. "Social Class and Ill Health: The Need for Further Research. A Reply to Antonovsky." Sociological Inquiry, vol. 37, Spring, 1967, (pp. 323-332. ) (Box 140, Folder A 491)
  - Linz, Juan J. "The Party System of Spain: Past and Future." Party Systems and Voter Alignments: Cross-National Perspectives, Seymour M. Lipset and Stein Rokkan, eds. New York: Free Press, 1967, (pp. 197-282. ) (Box 140, Folder A 512)
  - Lomax, Alan. "The Good and the Beautiful in Folksong." Journal of American Folklore, vol. 80, no. 317, July-September, 1967, (pp. 213-235. ) (Box 140, Folder A 506)
  - ______ "Special Features of the Sung Communication." Essays on the Verbal and Visual Arts, Proceedings of the 1966 Annual Spring Meeting of the American Ethnological Society, University of Washington Press, 1967, (pp. 109-127. ) (Box 140, Folder A 470)
  - Makler, Harry M. "American Social Research in Portugal: A Field Report." Journal of the American Portuguese Cultural Society, vol. 1, no. 2, Winter, 1967, (pp. 1-14. ) (Box 140, Folder A 517)
  - Merton, Robert K. "On the History and Systematics of Sociological Theory." On Theoretical Sociology: Five Essays, Old and New, by Robert K. Merton., New York: Free Press, 1967, (pp. 1-37. ) (Box 140, Folder A510)
  - ______ "On Sociological Theories of the Middle Range." lbid, 1967, (pp. 39-72. ) (Box 140, Folder A511)
    [*Note: Nos. A510 and A511 not available as articles.Instead are chapters in Merton's book " Theoretical Sociology." See BASR Project File No. B-1035]
  - Mitchell, Robert E. "Age and the Ministry: Consequences for Minister-Parishioner and Minister-Minister Relations." The Review of Religious Research, Vol. 8, No. 3. Spring, 1967, (pp. 1-10. ) (Box 140, Folder A 461)
  - ______ "Implications for Comparative Analysis Arising from Alternative Conceptions of Roles: An Example from the Ministry." Ibid. vol. 9, no. 1, Fall, 1967, (pp. 44-47. ) (Box 140, Folder A 450)
  - Nixon, Julian. "Federal Data Centers-Present and Proposed." Computer Privacy, Hearings before the Subcommittee on Administrative Practice and Procedure of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, Ninetieth Congress, first session, pursuant to S. Res. 25, March 14-15,1967, (pp.199-204. ) (Box 140, Folder A 485)
  - Sieber, Sam D. "Institutional Setting." The Role of Educational Research in Educational Change, the United States, Egon G. Guba, ed. Bloomington, IN: The National Institute for the Study of Educational Change, 1967, (pp. 3-19, 2 copies. ) (Box 140, Folder A 484)
  - ______ "Proposals for a Radical Revision of Research Training in Schools of Education." Preparing Research Personnel for Education, Clark and Worthen, eds. Washington, D.C.: Phi Delta Kappa and the American Educational Research Association, 1967, (pp. 27-33. ) (Box 140, Folder A 483)
  - ______, and David E. Wilder. "Teaching Styles: Parental Preference and Professional Role Definition." Sociology of Education, vol. 40, no. 4, Fall, 1967, (pp. 302-315. ) (Box 140, Folder A 474)
  - Sigal, Nan Markel. "The Unchanging Area in Transition." Land Economics, vol. 43, no. 3, August, 1967, (pp. 284-293. ) (Box 140, Folder A 507)
  - Sills, David L. "Research as an Instrument for Decision-Making." The Government of Associations, William A. Glaser and David L. Sills, eds. Totowa, NJ: Bedminster Press, 1967, (pp. 193-198, 2 copies. ) (Box 140, Folder A 435)
  - Weiss, Carol H. "Evaluation." President's Commission on Law Enforcement and Administration of Justice, Task Force Report: Juvenile Delinquency and Youth Crime, 1967, (pp. 404-408. ) (Box 140, Folder A 498)
  - ______ "Evaluation of In-Service Training." Targets for In-Service Training, Joint Commission on Correctional Manpower and Training, Washington, D.C., October,1967, (pp. 47-55. ) (Box 140, Folder A 496)
  - ______ "Utilization of Evaluation: Toward Comparative Study." The Use of Social Research in Federal Domestic Programs, a staff study for the Research and Technical Programs Subcommittee of the Committee on Governmental Operations of the House of Representatives, April, 1967. Vol. 3, (pp. 426-432. ) (Box 140, Folder A 497)
  - Zuckerman, Harriet. "Nobel Laureates in Science: Patterns of Productivity, Collaboration and Authorship." American Sociological Review, vol. 32, no. 3, June, 1967, (pp. 391-403. ) (Box 140, Folder A 463)
  - ______ "The Sociology of the Nobel Prizes." Scientific American, vol. 217, no. 5, November, 1967, (pp. 25-33. ) (Box 140, Folder A 488)
  - Adams, Walter. "The Cost of College-Who Pays the Bills?" The New York Statistician, vol. 20, no. 1, September-October, 1968, (pp. 3-5. ) (Box 140, Folder A 554)
  - Anderson, Bo, and Philip Hammond. "A Note on Selective Perception in Organizations." Acta Sociologica, Copenhagen, vol. I I -fase. 4, 1968, (pp.223-233. ) (Box 140, Folder A 560)
  - Bahr, Howard M. "Worklife Mobility Among Bowery Men." The Southwestern Social Science Quarterly, June, 1968, (pp. 128-141. ) (Box 140, Folder A 495)
  - ________,and Theodore Caplow "Homelessness, Affiliation,and Occupational Mobility." Social Forces, vol. 47, no. 1, September, 1968, (pp. 28-33. ) (Box 140, Folder A 494)
  - Bartenieff, Irmgard. "Research in Anthropology: A Study of Dance Styles in Primitive Cultures." Proceedings, Conference on Research in Dance, New York: Committee for Research in Dance (NYU), 1968, (pp. 91-104. ) (Box 140, Folder A 597)
  - Barton, Allen H. "Bringing Society Back In: Survey Research and Macro-Methodology." American Behavioral Scientist, vol. XII, no. 2, November-December, 1968, (pp. 1-9. ) (Box 140, Folder A 556)
  - ________, "The Columbia Crisis: Campus, Vietnam, and the Gheno." Public Opinion Quarterly, vol. 32, no. 3, Fall, 1968, (pp. 333-351. ) (Box 140, Folder A 555)
    [Also Quademi di Sociologia, vol. XVIII, nos. 1 & 2, 1969, pp. 124-158.]
  - _________ "Organizations: Methods of Research." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968, vol- I 1, pp. 334-343. "Personal Influence Revisited." Current Controversies in Marketing Research, Leo Bogart, ed. Market Research Council, Chicago: Markham Publishing Company, 1969, (pp. 113-126 ) (Box 140, Folder A 527)
    [Also in Revista di Sociologia, anno VI, n. 15, Rome, 1968, pp. 53-68.]
  - Bowers, William J. "Normative Constraints on Deviant Behavior in the College Context." Sociometry, Vol. 31, no. 4, December, 1968, (p. 370-385 ) (Box 140, Folder A 570)
  - Brunner, Edmund de S. and Coolie Verner "Adult Education." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, vol. 1, pp. 100-106. 1968 (Box 140, Folder A 528)
  - Caplovitz, David. "Consumer Credit in the Affluent Society." Symposium on Consumer Credit Reform, Law and Contemporary Problems, Autumn, 1968, (pp. 641-655.. ) (Box 140, Folder A 564)
  - Caplow Theodore, and Kurt Finsterbusch. "France and Other Countries: A Study of International Interaction." Journal ofConflictResolution, vol. 12, no. 1, March, 1968, (pp. 1-15. ) (Box 140, Folder A 518)
  - Caplow, Theodore, Howard M. Bahr, and David Stemberg. "Homelessness." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, vol. 6, 1968, (pp.494-499. ) (Box 140, Folder A 529)
  - Clark, Terry N. "Bertillon, Jacques." Ibid, vol. 2, 1968, (pp. 69-71. ) (Box 140, Folder A 530)
  - _________ "Institutionalization of Innovations in Higher Education: Four Models." Administrative Science Quarterly, vol. 13, no. 1, June, 1968, (pp.1-25. ) (Box 140, Folder A 547)
  - _____________, "Tarde, Gabriel." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, vol. 15, 1968, (pp. 509-514. ) (Box 140, Folder A 531)
  - _________ "Tourville, Henri de." Ibid, vol. 16, 1968, (pp. II 3-114. ) (Box 140, Folder A 532a)
  - __________, "Worms, Rene." Ibid, 1968, (pp. 579-581, 2 copies. ) (Box 140, Folder A 532b)
  - Cole, Stephen. "The Unionization of Teachers: Determinants of Rankand-File Support." Sociology of Education, (Winter, 1968), pp.67-68., Winter, 1968 (Box 140, Folder A 492)
  - ________, and Jonathan R. Cole. "Visibility and the Structural Bases of Awareness of Scientific Research." American Sociological Review, vol. 33, no. 3, June, 1968, (pp. 397-413.. ) (Box 140, Folder A 487)
  - Davison, W. Phillips. "Public Opinion: Introduction." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, vol. 13, 1968, (pp. 188-197 ) (Box 140, Folder A 533)
  - Etzioni, Amitai. "Organizational Dimensions and Their Interrelationships: A Theory of Compliance." People, Groups, and Organizations, B. P. Indik and F. K. Berrien, eds., New York; Teacher's College Press, 1968, (pp. 94-109.) (Box 140, Folder A 586)
  - _______. " 'Shortcuts' to Social Change?" The Public Interest, no. 1 2, Summer, 1968, (pp. 40-51. ) (Box 140, Folder A 519)
  - Glaser, William A. "Medical Care: Social Aspects." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, vol. 10, 1968, (pp. 93-100. ) (Box 140, Folder A 534)
  - Hyman, Herbert H. "Reference Groups." Ibid. vol. 13, pp. 353-361. Jaffe, A. J. "Cambios en la Fuerza Laboral, en la Economia y en la Poblacidn de Panam.* 1960 a 1967." Estadrstica Panameiza (Suplemento), Panamd: Direcci6n de Estadi.stica y Censo, August, 1968, ( 35 pp. ) (Box 140, Folder A 535)
    [Spanish translation by Carlos Gadpaille.]
  - __________, "Kulischer, Eugene." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, Vol. 8, 1968, (pp. 46-66. ) (Box 140, Folder A 536)
  - _________,. "Labor Force: Definitions and Measurement." Ibid, 1968, (pp. 469-474. ) (Box 140, Folder A 538)
  - __________, "Ogburn, William Fielding." Ibid, Vol.1, 1968, (pp. 277-281. ) (Box 140, Folder A 537)
  - Kadushin, Charles. "Power, Influence and Social Circles: A New Methodology for Studying Opinion Makers." American Sociological Review, vol. 33, no. 5, October, 1968, (pp. 685-699. ) (Box 140, Folder A 551)
  - ________, "Reason Analysis." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, vol. 13, 1968, (pp. 338-343, 2 copies. ) (Box 140, Folder A 539)
  - Landau, David, and Paul F. Lazarsfeld. "Quetelet, Adolphe." Ibid, 1968, (pp. 247-257. ) (Box 140, Folder A 540)
  - Lazarsfeld, Paul F. "An Episode in the History of Social Research: A Memoir." Perspectives in American History, Harvard University: The Charles Warren Center for Studies in Amerian History, vol. 11, pp.270-337., 1968 (Box 140, Folder A 552)
    [Republished in The Intellectual Migration: Europe and America, 1930-1960, Donald Fleming & Bernard Bailyn, eds. Cambridge, Harvard University Press, 1969]
  - ________, "Survey Analysis: The Analysis of Attribute Data." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, Vol. 15., 1968, (pp. 419-429. ) (Box 140, Folder A 541)
  - Levenson, Bernard. "Panel Studies." Ibid, vol. II, 1969, (pp. 371-379. ) (Box 140, Folder A 542)
  - McGuinness, Aims C., Herbert Menzel, Esther Fleishman, and Jean Garten. "The Medical Television Audience of the New York Academy of Medicine After Four Years." Bulletin of the New York Academy of Medicine, vol. 44, 1968, (pp. 332-345. ) (Box 140, Folder A 525)
  - Merton, Robert K. "The Matthew Effect in Science: The Reward and Communication Systems of Science are Considered." Science, vol. 159, no. 3810, January 5, 1968, (pp. 56-63. ) (Box 140, Folder A 493)
  - ___________, "Scientists and the'Matthew Effect." New Society, no. 277, January 18, 1968, (pp. 80-83. 2 copies. ) (Box 140, Folder A 501)
  - Nash, George. "The Current Status of Financial Aid Administration." The Journal of the National.Association of College Admissions Counselors, vol. 13, no. 2, June, 1968, (pp. 5-8. ) (Box 140, Folder A 548)
  - ________ "The History and Growth of Student Financial Aid." Ibid. no. 3, November, 1968, (pp. 11-17. ) (Box 140, Folder A 557)
  - __________, and Cynthia Epstein. "Harlem Views Columbia University." New York, July 8, 1968, (pp. 58-60. ) (Box 140, Folder A 550)
  - _________, and Patricia Nash. "Leads Columbia Could Have Followed." Ibid, June 3, 1968, (pp. 38-41. ) (Box 140, Folder A 549)
  - Schegloff, Emanuel A. "Sequencing in Conversational Openings." American Anthropologist, vol. 70, no. 6, December, 1968, (pp. 1075-1095. ) (Box 140, Folder A 592)
  - Sieber, Sam D. "Organizational Influences on Innovative Roles." Knowledge Production and Utilization in Educational Administration, Terry L. Eidell and Joanne M. Kitchel, eds. Eugene, OP,- Center for the Advanced Study of Educational Administration and University Council for Educational Administration, 1968, (pp. 120-142. ) (Box 140, Folder A 546)
  - _________, "Survey Research in Education: The Case of the Misconstrued Technique." Phi Delta Kappan, vol. XLIX, no. 5, pp. 273-276., January, 1968. (Box 140, Folder A 464)
  - Sills, David L. "Voluntary Associations: Sociological Aspects." International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, vol. 16, 1968, (pp. 362-379. ) (Box 140, Folder A 543)
  - Simmel, Arnold. "Privacy." Ibid. vol. 12, 1968, (pp. 480-487. ) (Box 140, Folder A 544)
  - Weiss, Carol H. "Validity of Welfare Mothers' Interview Responses." Public Opinion Quarterly, vol. 32, no. 4, pp. 622-633., Winter, 1968-69 (Box 140, Folder A 558)
  - Zuckerman, Harriet A. "Patterns of Name Ordering Among Authors of Scientific Papers: A Study of Social Symbolism and its Ambiguity." American Journal of sociology, vol. 74, no. 3, November, 1968, (pp. 276-291. ) (Box 140, Folder A 489)
  - Adams, Walter. "Financial and Non-Financial Factors Affecting Post High School Plans and Eventuations, 1939-1965." Proceedings of the American Statistical Association, Social Statistics Section, 1969, (pp. 99-124. ) (Box 140, Folder A 588)
  - _________, "Student Grade and Academic Self-Image-Relationships to College Entrance and Retention." The New York Statistician, vol. 21, no. 2, Nov.-Dec.,1969, (pp. 3-6. ) (Box 140, Folder A 573)
  - Schmidt, Gert. "The Industrial Enterprise, History and Society-. The Dilemma of German'Industrie-Und Betriebssoziologie." Social Science Information, vol. VIII, no. 6, December, 1969, (pp. 117-133. ) (Box 140, Folder A 565)
  - Bahr, Howard M. "Family Size and Stability as Antecedents of Homelessness and Excessive Drinking." Journal of Marriage and the Family, vol. 3 1, no. 3, August, 1969, (pp. 477-483. ) (Box 140, Folder A 582)
  - _______, "Institutional Life, Drinking, and Disaffiliation." Social Problems, vol. 16, no. 3, Winter, 1959, (pp. 365-375. ) (Box 140, Folder A 591)
  - __________,. "Lifetime Affiliation Patterns of Early- and Late-Onset Heavy Drinkers on Skid Row." Quarterly Journal of Studies on Alcohol, vol. 30, no. 3, September, 1969, (pp. 645-656. ) (Box 140, Folder A 583)
  - Barton, Allen H., Ljiljana Bacevic, and Dragomir Pantic. "Reception et Diffusion des Informations dans un Groupe de Formateurs de l'Opinion Publique dans une Societe Socialiste: Les Formateurs de l'Opinion Publique en Yugoslavie." L' Homme et la Societe, no 14, Oct.Nov.-Dec. 1969, (pp. 228-239. ) (Box 140, Folder A 569)
  - Brunner, Edmund de S. "Some Convictions About Social Research." Rural Sociology, September, 1969, (pp. 408-411. ) (Box 140, Folder A 562)
  - Cole, Stephen. "Teacher"s Strike: A Study of the Conversion of Predisposition into Action." American Journal of Sociology, vol. 74, no. 5, March, 1969, (pp. 506-520. ) (Box 140, Folder A 503)
  - Epstein, Cynthia. "Women and the Professions." New Generation, vol. 5 1, no. 4, Fall, 1969, (pp. 16-22. ) (Box 140, Folder A 572)
  - Etzioni, Amitai. "Agency for Technological Development for Domestic Programs." Science, vol. 164, no. 3875, April, 1969, (pp. 43-50. ) (Box 140, Folder A 589)
  - Glaser, William A. "Note on the Work of the Council of Social Science Data Archives 1965-1968." Social Science Information, vol. VIII, no. 2, April, 1969, (pp. 159-176. ) (Box 140, Folder A 553)
  - Jaffe, A. J. "Notes on Family Income Distribution in Developing Countries in Relation to Population and Economic Changes." Estadtstica, Journal of the lnter-American Statistical Institute, September, 1969, (pp.361-376. ) (Box 140, Folder A 568)
  - ___________, "Technology, Opportunity, and the Older Worker." Employment of the Middle Aged Worker, Washington, D.C.: National Institute of Industrial Gerontology, National Council on Aging, 1969, (pp. 281-341. ) (Box 140, Folder A 594)
  - Kadushin, Charles. "The Professional Self-Concept of Music Students." American Journal of Sociology, vol. 75, no. 3, November, 1969, (pp.389-404. ) (Box 140, Folder A 571)
  - Lomax, Alan. "Africanisms in New World Ncgro Music." Research and Resources of Haiti, Papers of the Congress on Research and Resources of Haiti, November 1967, New York: Research Institute for the Study of Man, 1969, (pp. 118-154. ) (Box 140, Folder A 598)
  - ___________, Irmgard Bartenieff, and Forrestine Paulay. "Choreometrics: A Method for the Study of Cross-Cultural Pattern in Film." Research Film, vol. 6, no. 6, 1969, (pp. 505-517. ) (Box 140, Folder A 599)
  - Merton, Robert K. "Behavior Patterns of Scientists." American Scientist, vol. 57, no. 1, 1969, (pp. 1-23 ) (Box 140, Folder A 595)
    [Also The American Scholar, vol. 38, no. 2, spring 1969, pp. 197-225
    *Note-only American Scholar article reprint in file]
  - Nash, George. "A Review of Financial Aid Research." Journal of the National Association of College Admissions Counselors, vol. 14, no. 1, June, 1969, (pp. 20-27 ) (Box 140, Folder A 567)
  - ___________, "The Role of the University as an Agent of Change." Current Campus Issues. Proceedings of the June 1969 Institutes on College and University Administration, Cambridge, MA: University Consultants, Inc., 1969, (pp. 79-102. ) (Box 140, Folder A 585)
  - ________, "Student Financial Aid, College and University." Encyclopedia of Educational Research, Ebel, Noll, and Bauer, eds., 4th. ed., New York: Macmillan, 1969, (pp. 1339-1359. ) (Box 140, Folder A 587)
  - Ritterband, Paul. "The Determinants of Motives of Israeli Students Studying in the United States." Sociology of Education, vol. 42, no. 4, Fall, 1969, (pp. 330-349. ) (Box 140, Folder A 577)
  - Segal, David R., and Marshall W. Meyer. "The Social Context of Political Partisanship." Quantitative Ecological Analysis in the Social Sciences. Mattei Dogan and Stein Rokkan, eds., Cambridge: MIT Press, 1969, (pp.217-232. ) (Box 140, Folder A 561)
  - Sieber, Sam D. "The School as a Social Model." TheHigh School Journal, vol. 52, no. 4, January, 1969, (pp. 175-181. ) (Box 140, Folder A 566)